Guide to the Rice University Committee on Public Lectures Records, 1946-1994 UA 168
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Committee on Public Lectures Records
1946-1994
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 168
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
This material includes minutes of the Rice University Committee on Public Lectures' meetings, lists of lecturers, suggestions for speakers, administrative files, and in some cases, texts of the lectures themselves.
Biographical Sketch
The Committee on Public Lectures is charged with the organization of an appropriate number of public lectures to be presented under the auspices of Rice University. It selects the lecturers and lecture topics for recommendation to the President of the University and arranges for the housing and entertainment of the lecturers. It also provides for the locations of and publicity for the lectures.
Scope and Contents
Included in box 1 are minutes of the committee's meetings, lists of lecturers, suggestions for speakers, administrative files, and materials pertaining to the lectures (including those lecturers asked, but did not speak). Boxes 2 and 3 contain copies of the individual lectures given by Edward Teller, C.P Snow, Buckmaster Fuller, James Stockdale, and Hyman Rickover among others.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
Received from Harold Hyman in 1981.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Subjects (Persons)
Hyman, Harold
- Series I: Administrative, 120277
  - Minutes, correspondence, notices, 1946-1949; 120251 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - List of lectures, 1947, 1951, 1953-1954, 1964-1980; 120252 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Early records and correspondence, 1952-1954; 120253 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Expenditures, 1967-1968, 1972-1973, 1976; 120254 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agendas, reports, minutes, correspondence, 1970-1972; 120255 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Membership lists, 1973-1974, 1974-1975, undated; 120256 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Funds, grant information, 1971, 1976; 120257 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Suggestions for speakers, 1972; 120258 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Agendas, reports, minutes, correspondence, 1972-1973; 120259 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lectures not given (correspondence), 1972-1973; 120260 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alumni Association correspondence, 1972-1973; 120261 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Information Services correspondence, 1972-1974; 120262 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Response to Self-Study, 1973; 120263 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Suggestions for speakers, 1973; 120264 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Agendas, reports, minutes, correspondence, 1973-1974; 120265 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1975; 120266 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Suggestions for speakers, 1974; 120267 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Agendas, reports, meetings, correspondence, 1974-1975; 120268 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Lectures not given (correspondence), 1974-1976; 120269 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Agendas, reports, minutes, correspondence, 1975-1976, 1976-1977; 120270 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Suggestions for speakers, 1975-1977; 120271 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Lectures not given (correspondence), 1977-1982; 120272 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Suggestions for speakers, 1978-1985; 120273 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Agendas, reports, minutes, correspondence, 1979-1984; 120274 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1982; 120275 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Memos, correspondence, 1993-1994; 121142 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series II: Lectures, 120278
  - Teller, Edward, 1/16/70; 120276 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Potter, David, 2/16/70; 120279 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Snow, C.P., 4/16/70; 120280 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Dupree, A. Hunter, 9/28/72; 120281 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Wilson, Harold, 1/12/73; 120282 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Meadows, Dennis, 3/27/73; 120283 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Hanks, Nancy, 9/25/73; 120284 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Weinberg, Alvin, 10/2/73; 120285 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hoyle, Fred, 11/73; 120286 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Whiting, Allen, 1/22/74; 120287 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Billington, James, 2/22/74; 120289 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fuller, Buckminster, 3/19/74; 120290 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Boulding, Kenneth, 9/17/74; 120291 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hanson, Howard, 11/74; 120293 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Eiseley, Loren, 2/18/75; 120294 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Price, Derek, 3/11/75; 120298 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cyert, Richard, 10/8/75; 120299 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Spiegelman, Sol, 11/5/75; 120300 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Huxtable, Ada L., 1/28/76; 120301 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bush, George, 3/23/76; 120302 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bridges, Harry, 4/13/76; 120304 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Neumann, Robert, 10/13/76; 120305 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Mosher, Charles, 10/20/76; 120306 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Barzun, Jacques, 11/17/76; 120307 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Broyles, William, 12/1/76; 120308 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Brimmer, Andrew, 4/13/77; 120309 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Sidey, Hugh, 9/27/77; 120310 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Berg, Alan, 1/18/78; 120311 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Meyer, Randall, 4/12/78; 120312 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Mathias, Charles, 9/15/78; 120313 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Djerassi, Carl, 10/31/78; 120314 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Kraft, Christopher, 1979; 120315 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Stockdale, James, 4/10/79; 120316 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Boorstin, Daniel, 4/79; 120317 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Alexander, Clifford, 11/13/79; 120318 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Martinez, Vilma, 1/21/80; 120319 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Simon, Herbert, 2/18/80; 120320 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Arnheim, Rudolph, 4/10/80; 120321 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Farenthold, Frances, 10/28/80; 120322 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Lerner, Max, 11/18/80; 120323 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Greeley, Andrew, 1/21/81; 120324 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Thomas, Lewis, 3/4/81; 120325 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Spuehler, Willy, 9/22/81; 120326 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Vanden Heuvel, William, 11/5/81; 120327 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Barthelme, Donald, 11/23/81; 120328 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Teller, Edward, 4/12/82; 120329 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Rickover, Hyman, 3/29/82; 120330 (Box 3, Folder 13)